<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://chrisridgers.github.io/Halve//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://chrisridgers.github.io/Halve//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-17T23:13:37+01:00</updated><id>https://chrisridgers.github.io/Halve//</id><title type="html">Chris Ridgers</title><subtitle>Just another damn blog from a guy on the internet.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Fresh Start</title><link href="https://chrisridgers.github.io/Halve//a-fresh-start/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Fresh Start" /><published>2017-06-17T22:32:30+01:00</published><updated>2017-06-17T22:32:30+01:00</updated><id>https://chrisridgers.github.io/Halve//a-fresh-start</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chrisridgers.github.io/Halve//a-fresh-start/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-fresh-start&quot;&gt;A Fresh Start&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014 I started a blog that was meant to be a documentation of working in tech following graduation from Univeristy.  It was supposed to be at least a place for me to market myself to potential employers, and ideally would have become something that would allow me to reflect on what I was doing and where I was going. To provide a semblance of clarity in what would otherwise be murky and uncharted territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as so often is the way of the world: life happened.  I immediately found myself hired by small startup called Mashbo.  After an exuberant celebratory post in which I displayed enthusiasm at the world to be, my blog died.  RIP blog 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I’ve been working at Mashbo on a number of projects and been consistently busy.  Clients have come and gone, projects have increased in size and complexity, our development processes have evolved significantly.  Right now, I’d say we’re the busiest we’ve ever been. After many weeks (130+) unable to find the time to sit and write, eventually even the platform I’d based my blog on became outdated.  Relearning and restructing that into something useful was an ambiguosly large task, one that that I didn’t have the time or headspace to sit down and treat properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently though, I’ve been considering the idea that some reflection is needed. So I’ve cleared my Saturday out and migrated my platform to Octopress 3 and GitHub Pages.  I’ll spend some time tomorrow hooking up my live domain, or I might not.  Right now, the idea of my own domain name above my site isn’t as important as just getting some stuff written down.  At some point, if this keeps going, I’ll want to turn this into a bit of my brand that I might use out there professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But right now, this is just a space.  For me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A Fresh Start</summary></entry></feed>